and they're paying pretty well. So, you
know, Anthropic will pay up to like
35,000 for a universal transferable
jailbreak. Um, OpenAI will now pay the
same, but they
>> what say that again? 35,000 for what?
>> A transferable jailbreak. So, you if you
put in like any question and it will
answer them, they'll pay $35,000.
>> Best part of Viking when you can just,
you know, critical think, right?
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
>> This week in Bug Bounty, there are two
major topics. One was from Yes, We Hack.
They're doing a new series called
Vulnerability
Vectors. And the first one is SQL
injection. So, they're going to
basically show you how to go from zero
to hero to learn SQL injection for bug
bounty hunters. Should be really cool.
So, go check that out. The last thing
that I had is also a part of this
weekend bug bounty from hacker 1. It is
a Mosilla VPN client rce. The
vulnerability is actually a path
reversal, but because the path reversal
allows you to overwrite startup script
files, it becomes rce. The Mac client is
not vulnerable. It's only the Windows
one. It's a really great write up. It's
a high. It paid six grand. Go check that
out at the link in the description. And
now we're back to the show. Thanks,
guys.
>> All right, dude. I've actually got a
pretty cool thing to start off this
episode with. Okay. Um, so I messaged
you the other day about hacking with
these like assistants, right? Like what
is the best way for me to do AI assisted
source code review? Y
>> and the reason I messaged you about that
because um I got a I got a spot check
from Hacker One uh for this specific
program that had an SDK that it wanted
us to like take a poke at and I was
like, "Okay, I definitely can't just do
this the oldfashioned way here." So read
this line.
>> So what you told me Yeah. Well, why
don't you give a quick summary to
listeners about what you told me uh I
should do and then I'll tell you what I
actually did and how it worked out.
Um, I don't remember this distinctly,
but I assume I told you to use cloud
code, boot it up, ask it, ask it to like
ingest it all line by line, create a
whole profile, which by the way, I did
that for I'm wearing my Kaido shirt
today. I did that for Emil with the back
end of Kaido. Like, hey, if you like
because basically he's found AI
completely lacking in his ability to
help him like, you know, develop.
>> Yeah.
>> I was like, I guarantee you I can make
it at least usable and like pretty good
for you. So, I did the same thing
probably I recommended to you. I
basically handed it the code and was
like, hey, read over this. create a full
structure of like how it works, why it
works, which pieces are interconnected,
what what is like a good coding
guideline based on like this code, not
just good Rust code in general. Kind of
merge those. And here's how you can find
more information about what Kaido is and
how it works and all those things. Um,
and so anyways, that's what I would have
told you to do.
>> Yeah, that's what you told me to do. I
don't know why you don't remember this
message, but I was like, "Okay, great."
It's probably because I didn't respond
to it. I just went ahead and did the
thing. I was like, "Yes, perfect. That's
exactly what I need." And then I went
and did the thing. And I was looking I
was going to grab cloud code like you
recommended
>> but then I was like I don't have a cloud
code like I don't have like a cloud
active right now. Yeah. And I was like
wonder what alternatives there are. And
I looked into it and you know Gemini has
a CLI client that came out recently
>> and um and so I grabbed
>> when I used it when they launched it was
terrible. It literally got API errors.
It was just down all the time and I
haven't even went back to it because it
was so bad. So I'm curious what your
experience is now that it's been
improved. Hopefully
>> it has been improved.
>> Yeah,
>> to some degree. Um I I I have seen some
videos uh per your recommendation of of
cloud code and it seems like cloud code
is a far,
you know, more refined product, right?
Um but
I I still opted to use Gemini because of
obviously the one reason that we all use
Gemini, which is the freaking massive
context window. Um, and and uh and it
actually has worked pretty well. So,
what what I've got now is I've got like
a gemini.md file set up and I've got
like so actually I did it with a
gemini.mmd file for this specific thing
that I'm talking about, but now I've got
like custom commands and extensions
built into um uh Gemini CLI that will
like perform the initial codebase
analysis, right? which is essentially
doing exactly what you said, going
through each file, you know, notating
what um I I had a couple sections I I do
like what is the the business function
of this file, you know, what are the
primary functions in this, you know,
specific file or class or whatever.
>> What are the security boundaries? like
what is the security related
functionality in this specific file,
right? And then and then summarize all
that and then have it go back and make a
summary of all the summaries and and
pull it all together into like this code
architecture
>> file that describes not only like the
functionality and the flow of data
throughout the application, but also
like the overall security architecture
like what are the core security
components? the security for this
specific app, you know, hinges on this
one function. You know, that's the
function that I want to know about like
right away, right?
>> Um,
>> so I've got it sort of outputting that
and and I think uh it didn't do amazing
>> like it did pretty good, right? like
like it it it identified a lot of the
the um I guess the core components that
that are necessary and and some of the
the attack vectors and also I had it
notate like threat model and like
>> why you know where people would be
attacking from sort of like what what
the attacker would have to have in a
specific situation to attack.
>> Was it using pro the whole time?
>> Yeah, it it was using well I had it use
flash for a little while and then I had
it switch back to pro and and I think
it's quite good with pro. I mean, it it
did a thorough analysis. It just didn't
lead me right to the vulnerability.
Right.
>> Right.
>> Um and but it did call out the section
of the app that had the vulnerability in
it. So, I was like,
>> you know, it was like definitely this is
one area that you're going to want to
focus on if you're doing a security
assessment. And lo and behold, I went
there and looked at that and I and I
found a vulnerability. So this this
target that yeah this target that I was
I was working on was like pretty high
>> is a very reputable company that has
this you know SDK that that they
released and it took me less than six
hours to find like a high high crit
impact vulnerability in this SDK.
>> I mean that's legit. That's awesome.
>> That's pretty good, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And it spun up PC's for me so
quickly and stuff like that where I
could just quickly validate. Frick,
dude. It's it's amazing. So, thank you
for that recommendation and and I'm sure
I'm sure you've got a similar workflow
with with cloud code in in place or is
it as built out as that or what?
>> Yeah, I'm actually really curious now
that you've mentioned that you have like
little extensions and stuff um kind of I
I talk a lot with Daniel Masler about
this exact stuff. Uh I think that cloud
code and Gemini CLI like you know
honestly it's just like an agentic
wrapping um where you can like expose it
to different things can be used for so
many different jobs and industries and
stuff but for hackers specifically I
think it can be super beneficial because
one a lot of what we're doing is like
let me go get this data from this data
source like whether it's subdomains or
you know whether it's kicking off a scan
on a virtual server or whether it's
whatever go and grab a a word list or
generating a word list and then a lot of
times it's doing other things like
deopiscating JavaScript, right, which we
we're going to talk about here in a
little bit, a tool that can do that. Um,
and then and then it's like synthesizing
like you said, where's the risk? And
then it's very often I think the most
beneficial thing is just spinning up
scripts. And so yeah, like you said with
cloud code, I very frequently will have
it like I'll just give it an HTTP
request from Kaido and say, "Hey, I'm
trying to test this for these things,
you know, go spin up some scripts that
go do it for me." And so it just it does
it right. It it can spin up a bunch of
scripts. It can do automation. It can
write for loops and stuff. And so it's
kind of able to automate just like a
deeper level. It's almost like if you
gave um Turbo Intruder, like if you gave
AI access to like Turbo Intruder, like
what could it do? It could do a lot of
really cool stuff.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Dude, I I think
there's So you hit the nail on the head
there with like spinning up scripts
being like the one of the primary things
that that these things will help,
especially if you're doing like an a
code uh review of an SDK or something.
>> Mhm.
>> Super super helpful. Um, but the other
thing that I came to appreciate this
time was just how fast it allowed me to
ingest the security controls in a
specific repo, right? Like like you know
it can go through assess the whole thing
and be like here's the security
controls, here's the security controls.
And then for me as a hacker, it just
>> like I think that's just how I think
about code a little bit, right? Is like
sort of surrounding these security
controls. Um and and so it just helps me
feel like I have a much more
comprehensive understanding of who might
be attacking from what perspective um in
in in the repo and maybe like the the
the whole threat model of the the the
codebase um by just saying hey here's a
security control here's a security
control and then sort of reverse
engineering from those security controls
saying okay well why is the security
control in place well it's so this
person doesn't do this
>> and now I've got you
your motivated actor and your you know
target goal right sort of built out
already.
>> Yeah. It's like having a single
interface for access to the data you
need which is like what are like the
sources and syncs and the security
controls and also an ideation partner
and honestly I think that sometimes for
humans like writing is thinking. So as
you're typing out your question to it,
you're actually clarifying your
thinking. Like when you're when you're
typing out like how would an attacker
attacker go about, you know, getting
into this function, like you're
clarifying your thinking and then
obviously it's going to clean up things
for you as it as it goes out and looks
for as it gs for like what actual uh
places that function's called, for
example. But it's like clarifying your
thinking while also serving you data
while also ideulating with you. Um yeah.
>> Yeah. Pretty solid. Pretty solid.
>> Yeah. I've been I've been specifically
your two bugs.
>> Well, I was going to say two nice
takeaway. One one high crit that that's
it on this repo, but uh I had two
specific takeaways. Do you want to make
a comment before I I drop?
>> No, mine's a nice like uh next next
topic. So, it's
>> transition. Okay. Yeah. Um so, here are
my my two takeaways that I'm going to
make sure that I integrate into my uh
prompting for future uh you know, SDK or
or white box analysis. Okay. One, have
it look at the tests. Right? If you have
a full codebase and you're not just
throwing it at like minified JavaScript,
>> look at the test files that are in there
and like have it look at all the test
files and say, are there any tests that
are validating a security control in
here?
>> Right.
>> That's cool. Yeah.
>> And and then, you know, then that points
you directly to the the single point
>> what they care about. Yeah.
>> For the for the security control, right?
Um so that's a good one. And then the
other one that I had it do which uh
helped me uncover the vulnerability was
look at where security controls are
implemented and then look at similar or
adjacent functions that might be missing
that same control
>> right um and it got me very very close
to the vulnerability. So
>> nice
>> cool stuff.
>> Yeah that's legit. Yeah. Yeah. So,
basically I've been using uh for the
last few days claude for cloud code for
doing basically AI safety kind of like
research uh open AI. Actually, this is a
topic for the pod. So, I'll just bring
this up. I think AI safety um programs
are like kind of neat if you are into
the AI stuff and they're paying pretty
well. So, you know, Anthropic will pay
up to like 35,000 for a universal
transferable jailbreak. Um, OpenAI will
now pay the same, but they
>> what I'm say that again. 35,000 for
what?
>> A transferable jailbreak. So you if you
put in like any question and it will
answer them, they'll pay $35,000.
>> No way.
>> Yeah.
>> What?
>> Yeah. On their bug bounty program. I
thought I'd mentioned this to you
before. Yeah.
>> No, dude. I did not know that that was
like that high stakes. I thought that
that's just still like an unsolved
problem. Like you you just always
>> It is an unsolved problem. So they so
they put some parameters around of
course like they have very specific
questions that they expect you to get an
answer to and they're like CBRN
bowarfare related questions. So they're
like really and you have to put them in
>> either word for word or like you can you
can technically have code that will do
like a string transform for like
synonyms or something
>> but you can't like completely change the
question in like whatever way you want
to. So that just you like slowly lead it
to the answer by like complete happen
stance. Like it still has to be like you
know a user is like relatively asking a
dangerous question.
>> My grandmother's dying and this is what
I need to do to save her.
>> Yeah. I mean so everyone has tried all
of those things. It's like getting very
safe and very difficult to bypass it. I
actually don't know if there have been
any.
>> Um so just shout out to their program.
They're really amazing. I actually got a
transferable full jailbreak and they and
they like it turned out they had like
turned off a part of their protection
classifiers and not told any of the bug
hunters and so I just happened to test
it during that perfect window. They
still paid me.
>> No way.
>> They they still paid the full bounty. So
like huge kudos to them. You should
definitely go check out their program.
>> So OpenAI historically has never paid
for safety issues. I think maybe
hopefully Anthropic has put on that
pressure through their program. So, you
have to still go apply for both of
these. Um, but they accept most people,
but OpenAI recently opened up their bio
bounty and it's the same thing. I think
they're only going to pay the first full
jailbreak at 35K and then the other ones
pay less. So, it's a little different.
Um, but I've been using a freaking
unbelievable bounty though.
>> Yeah. I mean, it allows you to invest a
ton of time, right, and resources and
and like effort and collaboration even
like, you know, splitting that still
makes it really worth it if multiple
people are involved.
Um, okay. And then third program here
I'm going to mention, they they released
a Kaggle bounty um for their their open
source models, which is really cool
because I'm sure that a lot of our
listeners,
>> what the heck's a Kaggle bounty?
>> So Kaggle.com is a website where like
secure or AI researchers post like I
don't know research competitions and I
think there are like there's often like
prompt injection stuff on there. Um.
>> Oh, okay. I see it. Nice.
>> Yeah, it's like it's just like an AI
kind of like benchmark model data set.
It's like a very data sciency website.
Um, and so then they're they're they
have one, if you Google Kaggle OpenAI
open source red teaming challenge or
something, it's a $500,000 challenge
where they're picking 10 winners. Now,
the listeners are not going to let get
this in time. It ends in two days. So,
but I do want to tell them about this
because it's really cool because I've
been using Claude Code to basically do
this testing with me and I think it
applies to bug bounty and um AI safety
in the same way. So, uh, what I did was
one, it's really cool to be able to run
this open source model locally. And
through my testing, I've realized how
good this thing is. So, it's actually
pretty dang safe. Like, it's pretty hard
to jailbreak or prompt inject.
>> Wow.
>> And it's really good at tool calling. It
works.
>> This is the one that they This is their
open source one that they released.
>> Yeah. So, they released two, 120 billion
parameter model and a 20 billion
parameter model. And the and they're
both mixture of experts, so they use far
less RAM than that, right? they're only
activating like a you know a sixth or an
eighth of the total network. So like
normally a 20B model would take like 20
gig of RAM but where this 20B model uses
mixture of experts and only uses a
subset of those of the of the model
weights
>> it can run on like you know 6 gig of RAM
or 7 gig of RAM so it's so it's pretty
nice and so the 20B model is used for
this challenge and the goal is to
basically um showcase some sort of like
novel harm and so like they're looking
for all kinds of unique stuff. Um we we
can link it in the show notes, but like
they're looking for like biases or like
prompt injection stuff or like can you
get it to recommend like um like uh
health things or therapist things that
are harmful like could you convince you
know could you have a prompt that where
it would like suggest someone commit
suicide like these things.
>> Have you tried cocaine?
>> Yeah, exactly. Yeah, anything like that
that would be harmful. Anyways, so I've
been using cloud code to both ideulate,
write the scripts, run it because it's
literally running on my machine to test
it and and analyze the output. And so
like I'm using, you know, this wrapper
to do the full thing locally and it's
working really well. Um it's really cool
about some use, man.
>> Well, yeah. It just runs on my Apple
silicon which is like quiet and fast and
stuff. Um which is pretty neat. But I
think people should This is actually as
I've been playing with it, I think if
you can write a really strong system
prompt, this is the first model that
people could use locally for totally
free. basically, of course, you're using
your GPU or your
>> um or your M series Mac, but um and
actually get like genuinely helpful
results from a local model and actually
have tool calling. It's not going to be
perfect. It's not going to be amazing.
Uh but I think it's the first model that
could potentially Oh, actually Ronnie
Loopin, everybody knows that. I
>> was going to say, yeah,
>> he's using it. Uh he was able to go from
like u I'm going to I'm going to look up
our messages really quickly
>> because he he sent something pretty
crazy in our group chat. He was like
saying he utilized this for some part of
his product or something like that and
was getting some really good results
from it.
>> Exactly. Yes. That's what I was going to
call out. He and I started DMing about
it. He was able to go from
Gemini 25 Pro. So he So for anyone who
doesn't know obviously Top Hacker Lupin,
he's been on the show many times, but he
he has a product called Deppy that does
like
>> um what's it called?
>> Supply chain
>> supply chain. Yeah. Supply supply chain
attacks. and he used AI in a bunch of
different ways. He moved the AI autofix
feature from Gemini 25 Pro all the way
down to GPT open source 20B and it works
even better, he said. So anyways, if
people are building cool stuff, they
should definitely try it out.
>> Wow, dude, that is uh that is pretty
exciting for security people because
having an offline model is really
important for stuff. So maybe we'll uh
we'll work on some integrating some of
that stuff into Kaido as well.
>> Yep.
>> Um yeah, dude. Crazy. I know we spend a
lot of time talking about AI stuff
nowadays, but like it is very important
that we do that because uh there is a
lot of crazy stuff happening and there's
a massive shift going on. So um yeah, I
think I think it's important. But with
that, I will jump to
>> my my next favorite topic which is
CSPTs.
>> Yep.
>> Um so let me go ahead and share this uh
go ahead and share this article really
quickly here. Um, this is an article
entitled cash deception plus CSPT, which
actually should be CSPT plus cash
deception, but it is what it is. Um, and
uh, this is by Ziri or Zer, I don't know
how to how to pronounce that, but um,
I've seen some great stuff coming out of
this researcher. And essentially, this
is just a nice little write up here um
explaining how he was able to exploit a
uh cash deception that was seemingly
impossible to exploit because it
requires token um to using a CSPT. Okay,
so here's the little let's see where's
the actual little graph here. Okay, here
it is right here. So the attacker sends
to the victim you know a CSPT which
forces the victim you know which hijacks
a fetch request that contains their you
know session and their curve token
automatically added by whatever you know
JS middleware they had you know in the
client side there and then an
authenticated request is sent to the the
back end the data and this authenticated
request now ends with CSS right so
because he was able to fully control the
path so he's able to in invoke the cache
deception um utilizing the CSPT and then
when it comes back from the server
that's getting cached at the CDN level
um because it's actually got the valid
values now that the CSRF token is
included cached at the CDN level and
then the attacker can go then retrieve
that. So I just thought this was a
really creative CSPT. Yeah.
>> Yeah, that's really cool.
>> Yeah. and and and so you know those CS
those um cache receptions that are out
there where you can get values cache but
you have to have something in the
request that you can't send uh those
might be exploitable if you can chain it
with CSPT. So really great really great
finding here by um Zer
>> that feels to me like uh kind of the
next level of I mean you know this is
maybe a little bit of a hot take but I
feel like the fact that bugs get more
and more esoteric over time means the
industry is actually getting more secure
over time right like you have to jump
through more hoops you know you maybe
you don't agree I saw your skepticism
but like I just feel like the fact that
you know things like CSPT are being like
um found and used and exploited um by
buck hunters. I think it like really
shouts to the fact that that like
there's less low hanging fruit than
there was in the past. And uh I think
that it's neat, like just so cool that
it ends up resulting in extreme
creativity basically from researchers to
come up with really cool stuff like
this. Like you said, it was a cash
reception that was not really that
exploitable
>> and then now you found a way to make the
victim cash it for you. Just super cool.
>> Yeah, super super solid finding. I do
agree and I think CSPT is I guess the
how common CSPT is becoming because of
the need for for this is largely born
from the fact that same site cookies are
messing up a bunch of other client side
bugs
>> and CSPT you know allows you to trigger
requests and get things like curf uh
from the same site right so I think that
that you're right I think it is an
evolution in client side security that's
pushing us to find these more um these
more complex uh attack types. And to be
honest, it's been great to see because I
freaking love chains. So,
>> he also he also calls out Jorge is the
guy that wrote this, Jorge D. Costa. Um
and he he also calls out three
resources. Matan Bear's excellent
introduction to CSPT, his CSPT talk in
Spanish, and uh a CSPT presentation by
Maxen Schmidt. So, um, those are also
some great resources if you're not
already up to date on on CSPT. Um, and
cash reception is like pretty well
documented. I think there's some good
good stuff out there for that. So,
>> yeah.
>> Sweet.
>> Where where do we want to go next, man?
>> Um, the question is slice is a little AI
related. Let's just mention five real
quick.
>> Oh my gosh, dude. This is such a funny
thing. Go for it. Go for it.
>> I'm trying to think about the best way
to share it. Let me see if I can go to
to the pod. Maybe
>> uh just they'll put it up on the screen.
>> All right, cool. Yeah, so put it up on
the screen. Uh basically, there is a
researcher who has been um doing lots of
really cool stuff on Microsoft's bug
bounty program. He's up and coming, you
know, he is very young, only has a few
bugs under his belt, but um me and
Justin and a few other guys all get DMs
from him because he gets so excited
about it. He like immediately like
messages us with cool findings. But he
he sent me this message on Discord that
just screams bug bounty passion and it's
like if you could invest in this guy,
you should invest a ton of money because
he's definitely going to make it. He he
tweeted or sorry, he he he DM'd me on
Discord. Yo man, I just figured out a
sick method. Whenever my power goes out,
I can still find tons of bugs from the
JS files downloaded locally on my
laptop. Aka, he's thinking whenever
there's a hurricane that makes him
unable to hack, he's not going to stop
hacking. He's just gonna get out his
computer and start analyzing the
JavaScript
>> and start raw dogging the JS files that
he has on his local system.
Dude, yeah, this guy has been finding
some really, really awesome stuff. And I
think there's uh I think he sent I think
I don't know if he's released the
article yet that he sent me, but he's
got some really good uh articles coming
out. Um yeah, so it's EFAV
on on X. Um definitely give him a
follow. But this this like you said man
is like very high signal like bug bounty
addict for sure.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Completely addicted to bug
hunting which is exactly what leads to
success. So
>> yeah man. Yeah it's you love to see it.
This is the this is why bug bounty gets
so so great results in my opinion is
like this is what it does to people.
Yep.
>> Is it gets you like this where you're
just like oh well you know I could still
read the I have done this before 100%.
Like I was on a flight. Yeah. On a
flight like I've, you know, the internet
is crap. It keeps dropping. I'm not
getting productive. And you know what?
Screw it. I'm just gonna take these JS
files, format them, and just like really
dive deep on them. Um,
>> speaking of things you can do on a
flight.
>> Oh, dude.
>> I I just shared this with Justin before
the call, so I'll let him I'll let him
talk about it.
>> I lost my mind when you showed me this.
This is so cool. Okay. Um All right.
I'll take it. I'll take it. So, yeah.
Uh, freaking Reszo drops this in the
dock right before this this episode and
I just got totally nerd sniped by it and
we're starting like 15 minutes late
because I was like, "This is amazing."
Um, this is a Jeez. Yeah. Like I guess
I'll share this tweet on the screen. Um,
this is a service that I guess was put
out by a AI company. Can you find the
name of that AI company while I'm
yapping about it, Joseph?
>> Yeah. Um, but essentially you can
communicate with an LLM via DIG.
So you can do it on like a plane uh and
just, you know, typically there's DNS
pass through on a plane. Um, and so you
can just dig at ch.at, which is like
also an S tier domain. I don't know how
they're using this for for that,
>> but um, dig.at
at and then just put in double quotes,
you know, what is whatever your query is
and then make sure you specify the txt
type um you know DNS type and then it
will just over DNS kick back a txt
record to your dig with the response
from the LLM dude.
>> So freaking cool. Yeah. So it's a
company called Deep AI and in fact if
you go to ch.at at. Apparently, it's
available via SSH and curl as well. But
the coolest one by far is DIG chatting
over DNS text records.
>> Wow, dude. Yeah, look at that. Curl,
SSH,
and DIG. No logs, no accounts, free
software.
>> Yep. It feels like it feels like
something a hacker would build.
Obviously, these guys are, you know, AI
or probably just devs, but it feels like
something that somebody in the hacker
community would build. So, really cool.
>> Absolutely, man. Yeah, I'm totally going
to use this on a plane. This is uh
extremely extremely cool. Thank you for
showing me this. I really did lose it
when you showed it to me. I was like,
>> there there are just some projects like
terminal.sh
uh SSH where you can like buy coffee
over SSH. There are just some things
that like the idea itself is so clever
and cool that even if you don't use it
or it's not that beneficial. It's just
like yes, hackers did that. It's like
find some way to do that, you know?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I love Turbin, too. Have you
ever used Turbin? I don't
>> uh it's like paste bin but you can just
do it directly from your terminal. So
you just cat cat something pipe it to
term bin 999 and then it just uh it like
gives you a link where you can share it
to your friends.
>> Oh no that's really cool. I need to
start using that.
>> Yeah it's very good.
>> Um decent transition into tools if we
want to look at talk about uh search
cyber.
>> Oh yeah yeah um this was awesome. They
they released this at um okay so let me
let me back up. This is uh tools by
search light cyber. Search Light Cyber
is the Asenote squad, right? They got
acquired. Um, and they released this
Search Light Cyber Tools that has uh
that is their website that is a
conglomerate of all the tools that asset
note has sort of released over the past,
you know, however long they've been
absolutely crushing it. Um, yeah, and
and I think that there are a couple on
here that are much better for beginners,
right? like the subdomain takeover
scanner and um uh even even surf. I'm
not like I feel like I would do what
what surf does there a little bit I
would do it more efficiently on a
command line with like even just tools
that I've got in a normal Unix box. Um,
but New Towner and No Waff Please are
two uh tools that are built into the
Search Light Cyber um website now that
they've got that uh are super helpful,
specifically New Towner. So I don't have
to like configure my AWS credentials,
spin up a bunch of stuff in different
regions of the world. I just give it a
URL and it and it tries it from, you
know, seven different regions or
whatever. That is extremely helpful.
Yeah, it's basically hosted versions of
all their tools and the website is
tools.slcyber.io.
>> Yeah. The other one on here is no waff
which is the tool that they released I
think at nomcon 2024. Um that allows you
to bypass WS by inflating the request
size. Um there is both a burp and a
Kaido uh extension for no AF please. But
um if you want to just paste the raw
HTTP request into the search light cyber
website, it will automatically inflate
the size of that request for you. Um and
you could just paste it back into your
proxy and resend it to see if that gets
around the W as well. So kind of like a
quick and dirty method if you're doing
something um where you're not access to
your normal security tools.
>> Yeah. And obviously their word lists are
lots of other places, but you can get
them here, which is kind of cool in case
you just have this pulled up for example
because you want to, you know, just have
a bunch of tools in one place.
>> Yeah, I was actually watching Michael's
presentation when he released this. I
think they actually did a bunch of stuff
>> to the word list as well. It's not just
like download their their normal word
list. They like
>> um they created a way for you to like
sync down the like new word list
changes. And um I wish I I I just
thought of it now when you mentioned
word list.
>> Yeah, that's really cool. Let me open
that back up.
>> But I didn't get to fully like check it
out before the episode. So there's
definitely some changes to the asset
word list um that that they now got on
the search light cyber website. Um and I
think that's probably I think Michael
said that that is one of their most used
things is their word list because
they're just like super S tier.
>> Um
>> definitely worth investigating.
>> That's awesome.
>> Yeah.
>> Sweet, dude. All right, let's see. Let's
see what we got left here.
>> Yeah, so we have the
what's it called? Slice. Yeah, we have
slice and then we have EPA which are
both kind of AI related and then you
have your bug bounty hunters report
which is not AI related.
>> Okay, why don't you take Slice and I'll
I'll take a look at the bug bounty
report real quick.
>> Okay, sweet. So, Caleb Graass, our
friend who lives relatively close to our
friend uh Justin and is a top hacker. Um
he's like a legit guy. He um is a good
friend of ours. And he released a tool
called Slice, which is basically
>> a tool that does like has an LM but also
static analysis of code. So, it does
like SAS scanning. Honestly, we should
have talked about it right after we
talked about what you did with Gemini
CLI, I guess. Yeah. Yeah, it's
definitely relevant.
>> Did you um did you try this at all? Did
you try to run any kind of CodeQL
queries across your SDK?
>> So that's that's the the situation with
with this like I think this is a super
amazing tool. I am not as comfortable
with code and like
>> same
>> um creating those patterns and I think
in the the specific language that I was
working with uh there just wasn't as
intuitive patterns for these sort of
things.
>> Um
>> so I think this is really good for you
know creating uh I think the example
that he he used was uh like a C codebase
or something like that where there's
like really nice patterns for specific
types of vulnerabilities. Um, but it
essentially takes a CodeQL query,
filters the results, and then ranks them
by by criticality. Um, so it's got like
those those
>> pieces of I think there's four pieces,
parse, query, filter, and rank.
>> Um, and it seems pretty built out in
order to accomplish that exact workflow.
CodeQL, and then using LLM to sort of
sort and evaluate them. um very high
value I think for for C codebases at
least.
>> Yeah, I think in general the idea of
like what he basically did in case
anyone's curious is
>> um AI had found this vulnerability
um based on this other writeup but it
found it you know some guy used AI to
find a vulnerability but it found it
like one in a 100 times or something and
I think he was curious like can we make
this more reproducible? Can I make this
better? And I think reverse engineering
from that way is like a really powerful
mental model. And so then he was able to
eventually, you know, get slice to like
find it much more consistently. You can
see here, you can see here
>> across 10 times it found the bug every
time it says right above the table.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Exactly. I was thinking that it
might show like nine out of 10 or 10 out
of 10 here, but I couldn't find it in
that. Um, obviously different models are
going to do better and worse, but and
they're going to cost more and less and
of, you know, obviously there's
non-determinism, but I think that this
is extremely cool. And honestly, I think
like I'm sure there already something
exists out there that is um that does
Oh, this is his blog by the way. So,
it's both on his blog and then of course
it's on um it's on the tool is on
GitHub. But I think that um Oh, man.
What was I going to say?
>> I'm not sure. But this this
vulnerability that it discovered was uh
CVE 202537778
which is the Linux kernel SMB uh
vulnerability that came out recently. Um
so you know it is attacking a lower
level a low lower level codebase here.
um which is really cool to see, you
know, and
>> yeah, he uses GPT5 in the writeup and
and I think Expo also noted that they
saw just a massive increase in in
functionality
>> when they started using GPT5. So I think
that could be um something really big
for a you know AI as applied to security
is just making sure you're using GPT5
and just tanking the cost that it it
takes right now. Yeah, I will say uh the
the thing I remembered well I'll comment
on GP5 then I'll go back to what I
remembered for GBT5 you do have to use
thinking and then honestly obviously the
higher cost of thinking like the more
thinking is like even better and GPT5
pro is insane but it gets pretty
expensive. Um, the thing that I
remembered was I was going to say that
I'm sure there are some CodeQL like text
to CodeQL things out there already, but
something like this that's like more
dynamic and more um kind of security
aware and intelligent with like really
good system prompting I think has the
ability to find like bugs kind of at
scale if you run CodeQL across GitHub. I
don't ever I don't know what happened to
that old program. I don't think it
exists anymore where they used to pay
for like really good CodeQL queries and
stuff. But yeah,
>> kind kind of a neat idea for finding
bugs at scale, especially if you don't
even care about bug bount. You just want
to find some cool cvees or some cool
vulnerabilities. It's a great path to
take
>> for sure. Yeah. I don't know what
happened to that program. That that is
uh
>> I think I remember it shutting down, but
I don't know why.
>> Dude, they also shut down Google's um
>> mobile program. No, no, the the the
mobile program where like every app
above 100 million installs was in scope.
>> Oh, they took that out?
>> Yeah. I was bummed because my girls had
like this app that they were playing and
it has a ton of installs and I was like,
what if I just, you know, don't mind if
I do take a look, you know?
and uh and you know win some reputation
points with the kiddos. Uh but now I'm
not allowed to do that. So
>> lame.
>> Sweet, dude.
>> Yeah. Um definitely definitely cool to
see these tools pop up. Um I think
Caleb's been working on this sort of
thing for a while now and I think he's
got a good workflow going now and this
is definitely uh gonna I think he's got
a cool niche here too which is reverse
engineering CVS that come out very very
quickly. very relevant to what he does,
you know, but just a very awesome tool.
And I think I think a lot of um
>> I think a lot of recon boys could could
benefit from this. Or maybe like a recon
boy and a you know,
CVE reverser pair up,
>> you know, and and say, "Okay, you
reverse the CV, you pass me the pock,
and then I'll spray it." And then I
think you could really make a good
amount of money off of just like for
both of them, right?
>> Off of just that little combo there.
>> Yeah.
>> Um All right. So, uh the other thing
that we had on here was um Slanzer, who
we talk about on the pod all the time,
>> released a Kaido plugin called Ebka,
>> uh which is an AI plugin for Kaido.
>> Um and it seems to have a ton of
functionality. He was very thorough in
implementing all of the different um
pieces of Kaido. And essentially what it
what it allows you to do is just um
control Kaido from inside of Cloud Code
or via um he I think he also has like an
interface built right in directly to
Kaido. Right.
>> Yeah. So I'll share my screen. Well, if
it'll let me
>> go for it.
>> Yeah. Screen window.
We gota we gota I definitely think we
should continue sharing screen but we
also got to make sure that we are
>> still articulating it. That's true for
the audio.
>> So basically I'm sh I'm sharing Kaido.
>> Um and so there's like the little model
selector up here and this may have
improved. I haven't installed it in a
few days, but um basically you have the
tab for the
>> um what's it called for the plugin and
then you can basically say something
like you know are there any analytics
requests in my HTTP history?
>> Um if so make a filter for them.
So like one like this is a bunch of
different tool calling of course like
right it's like checking your history
finding things doing some sort of search
coming back then like you know
automatically making the filter and then
doing all of that kind of oneshot. So
like right now so the tool calls he's
having it use are like list by HTTPQL
and then view request by ID and then
create filter preset. And so the way it
um kind of works in like a chaining way
like that's like pretty powerful. And so
I think that it probably has a lot of
cool use cases. I think we should, you
know, try to integrate this or at least,
you know, build something similar into
Shift. But
>> yeah,
>> really neat.
>> Yeah, I think I think Shift, you know,
Shift was kind of like the it has some
of these these features, right, where
you can utilize AI to interact with um
with the Kaido interface, but it's a lot
less iterative like you said, right?
It's just kind of like, okay, you know,
uh build a filter for this. Oh, wow.
That was actually that was quite a a a
filter that it generated there. That's
very long.
>> And these are all just like requests. So
I it's and you know, of course, it's all
about how you use the AI. This usually
blocks way too much when I try this
little PC. And I haven't found like
another great use case, but I only use
this for like an hour or something. I
didn't spend a lot of time. I think
there are probably some really great use
cases like find requests that look like
this and then send them to replay for me
or whatever. So, like could you imagine
it going and finding all the requests
that you would have found interesting
and putting them in replay for you so
then you can go review them? Like
there's probably some really cool stuff
here like that, you know?
>> Yeah, I like I like the, you know,
nature the more traditional MCP nature,
right? Like Shift was kind of uh right
on the edge of like MCP um when it was
first coming out. So, we didn't fully
implement that, but he's got that in in
place here. and you can kind of keep
that same context and ask follow-up
questions and and uh it's sort of built
around that whole tool calling
structure. So um I know Senzer is really
committed to the codebase as well. He's
like um well I mean he's committed to
the codebase quite a few times one might
say but uh he's he's committed to the
codebase like he's making updates to it.
He's using it actively himself. Um so I
I definitely expect for this to continue
to improve and and I think he's using it
not for directly within Kaido though. I
think he's hooking it into like cloud
code or cloud desktop, right?
>> Yep. Yeah. Because it's MCP based, you
don't have to call it, right? You don't
have to use the plugin, which is really
neat.
>> Yeah, that is which actually means uh
back to our idea earlier about like
using kind of claude as just like a
general assistant, which I will do
often. Um, yeah, we didn't really expand
out that full section. Let me just
circle back to that for just a second.
So, not only can you use it for like
researchy stuff and SDK stuff like
you're talking about because you have
full control over these system prompts
and commands, you can also have it like
manage your to-do list and like help you
like prioritize what you're going to
work on for the day. And it can also,
you know, if you have like good context
and files. So, one thing that Daniel
does and that I'm trying to add more of
is like having like context files for
like, hey, here's what I'm passionate
about, here's what I'm working on,
here's what my family's like, whatever.
so that it can pull that in dynamically
if it needs to as a part of like writing
some content or writing a blog or
whatever but
>> decision.
>> Yeah, exactly. But because it also has
access to MCP, you could in that same
interface basically just have a terminal
up. And so if you are kind of like
hacking on the command line and then
you're like having it write scripts for
you and then you can even say things
like, "Yeah, there was a request in
Kaido that had this kind of a path, use
the Kaido MCP to then like, you know,
pull up that path and then incorporate
it." And so that'd be pretty neat to
like also give your assistant kind of
access to Kaido. So now you have like an
AI assistant who's doing all of those
things but but also has access to Kaido.
So
>> Wow. Yeah. There's there's a lot of gez
there it's hard for me to understand
right now you know what is the right
thing to modify my my workflow with
because I feel like I can get lost in AI
land
>> for a while you know and I think
>> um what what is what are the AI things
that I can implement today that are
going to give me the highest ROI on and
make me a more efficient hacker right
now and I think from my experimentation
lately it is offsourcing you know
outsourcing these these small tasks pass
with like shift agents or um whatever
like hey fuzz this for
>> you know open redirect or whatever and
then um you this piece of essentially
allowing cloud cloud code or gemini CLI
or whatever to slurp up a whole repo and
now let me like get a mental model of
the security posture of that repo
>> um very quickly I think just really
really helps me get into the meat of
hacking a little bit more
>> um quickly. So, I mean, obviously
there's always going to be hack bots
that are like doing crazy things, but I
think these are really helpful for me.
>> Yeah, I think that the best mental model
for how and where and when to use them.
And obviously, you can't always know
this without experimentation, but it's
just like don't invest a ton of time.
Like don't spend 3 weeks, you know,
incorporating a bunch of stuff into this
thing or whatever because like it might
go obsolete or it might not be as
beneficial to you or it might be too
much of a time sync. like anywhere that
you can get kind of like quick wins to
like just speed up your current workflow
is where you should try to integrate it,
I think.
>> And that's the thing I like about um the
source code review agent thing too is
like I can spend a little bit of time in
there investing in like prompts
>> and refining my prompts for that. And I
feel like that's not ever going to be
some cost because even if it's not
Gemini CLI that I'm using, I'm I'm going
to be using Claude or something. and and
those prompts themselves have value as I
continue to refine them for what I want
>> personally out of a you know an AI
assistant and then eventually these
things are just going to get better and
better and better at giving me what I'm
looking for which is what's described by
the prompt right
>> but yeah you're right you can just copy
and paste that like hey do this research
or do this scaffolding prompt over into
a different system and like you and like
you said um I don't think it's sunk cost
for code review like with SDKs because
that is already such a time inensive
task that you would have had to do. So
you have the extra, you know, bandwidth
there at the beginning to put a little
bit of sunk cost into it because it's
saving you so much time on the back end.
>> Yeah. Yeah. This code this codebase that
I was reviewing was pretty small and and
um but I I'm very confident that I got
>> would you would you have found it that
like or how long like that I feel like
that's the real question is like how
long would it have taken you to found
it? Would you have found it? Would you
not would you have not even been
interested in the program if had had you
not had the ability to use AI to help
with it?
>> I certainly would have found it. It
would have taken a lot longer. I
probably would have had to sync
>> I probably condensed my knowledge like
getting knowledge of the application,
you know, into like 30 minutes to an
hour and getting comfortable with the
codebase, right? I still spent a good
amount of time reading through
documentation and stuff like that, but I
I will spend, you know, normally four or
five hours kind of just feeling groovy
with the code base, you know?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Jeez, do not do anything with that
little dance. Feeling groovy with the
code.
>> You just love You just love these uh
relationship analogies. Soljer's really
committed to his thing. You know, we got
to get intimate, get groovy,
>> you know. Yeah, snuggler.
>> Um, but it it takes time to get, you
know, intimate with the codebase and and
I think this really expedited that.
>> So, cool.
>> Sweet. Uh,
>> got a wrap. Do we have anything else we
wanted to hit here?
>> I mean, you've mentioned Jim CL like 15
times. You got to talk about this post
message target origin bypass.
>> Okay. All right. Okay. This is this is
not specifically um I I I will I will
talk about this. Um, this is for code
assist for Google. Uh this is a Google
VRP writeup that was um uh that was
publicized that was what am I trying to
say? Disclosed. There we go. Um and it
was paid 20K. Uh researchers Jacob
Doaraki.
And uh I just thought I just wanted to
like put this out there for any of you
guys that are intimidated by hacking
Google because I just don't feel like
this was that super insane of a bug
>> like this. And you know,
>> there you go, Jacob. That's what Justin
thinks about your bug.
>> No, no, no. Jacob, Jacob, Jacob, Jacob.
Dude, that's not what I'm trying to say.
Like, it's an amazing bug. I'm so like
you you crushed it. But this is not like
some of the other crazy
>> orange size research, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it's it's a he and
and I one of the things I like about
this write up, Jacob did an excellent
job with is he he shows the train of
thought, too. He's like, "Okay, so
here's how you link GitLab to Gemini
Cotus' tools." Okay. And then here's the
OOTH flow. And you'll notice in the
state parameter there's like this JSON
blob. Very reasonable thought, right?
That's not like a super crazy, you know,
mega um Google client side hacker um
necessary thought, right? It's like,
yeah, okay, let's see what that does.
And he says, as it turns out, the
redirect URI page for this uses the
value of the origin key passed in from
that state parameter um to verify the
post mega message target origin. And so
it it shows the the code snippet and
essentially it just parses the state,
grabs the origin and then does
origin.ends with
>> uh
>> is that JavaScript like he he can he can
just see that right on straight on the
slirect uh page, right?
>> Say it again.
>> Like that's that's like client side code
that he you can go find. That's not like
a server side check.
>> No, no, no. He just found it on on the
client side. Cool. And um and so
essentially, you know, he's he's
this allows him to to bypass the the
whole flow here uh and with just using
attacker.comcode
assist.google.com.
Yeah.
>> And uh and so yeah, he's able to do some
really awesome stuff with this. Um and
but I just wanted to encourage you guys
and leak the oath code because this is
like the kind of stuff that is there.
You just got to look for it. And it's a
lot more common even in Google right now
because of how fast everything is going.
And and Jacob did an excellent job of,
you know, having that requisite
knowledge and then jumping right on this
as as code assist is is getting released
and as it's being debed on constantly
and snagging up a super nice 20k bug
from Google um for this for this report.
So pretty sick.
>> Sweet, dude.
>> I think that is mostly it. We'll talk.
We We'll save some of these other little
smaller ones for next week, maybe.
>> Sweet. Yeah, sounds good. Dude, it feels
good to be back on the uh on the pod.
It's been like It's been like three
weeks for us, right? Because we recorded
a ton before Defcon.
>> Yeah, we recorded a lot. We did a whole
bunch of solo episodes, so it's the
first time we've been on the call
together for a while.
>> Yes, man. Good to good to talk with you,
man. All right, that's a wrap. Peace.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctv.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunter guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.
[Music]